Hi, welcome to session eight of learn and master guitar,
嗨，欢迎来到 learn and master guitar 第八节课，
here we're going to talk about some very key concepts
这里我们将讨论一些非常关键的概念，
in your guitar learning your guitar knowledge,
学习你的吉他知识，
we've covered the barre chords on the sixth string,
我们已经讲到了第六弦上的横按和弦，
now we're going to cover the barre chords on the fifth string,
现在我们要讲第五弦上的横按和弦，
there are barre chords on other strings,
在其他弦上还有横按和弦，
but generally once you've covered the sixth and fifth,
但通常一旦你掌握了第六弦和第五弦，
you've pretty much got a good handle on what you need to do,
你就很好地掌握了你需要做的事情，
so you're halfway there,
所以你已经走到了一半，
if you've made it through this far through the six string barre chords,
如果你已经通过了第六弦横按和弦，
we've got half more, five more forms are going to learn the five string barre chords
我们还有五个形式的横按和弦学习，
and then you are set and ready to go.
然后你就准备好了。
Okay in our music, how music works section,
好的，在我们音乐如何工作部分，
we're gonna cover a couple of key concepts
我们将涵盖几个关键概念，
dealing with keys and key signatures,
涉及调和调号，
how to determine the key,
如何确定调，
how to how to drive that information from the major scale
如何从大调音阶中提取信息，
and then a very important information
然后一个非常重要的信息，
as you begin playing with other musicians and playing in different settings is
当你开始与其他音乐家一起演奏并在不同的环境下演奏时，
how to determine the key from just looking at a piece of music,
如何仅通过观察一段音乐来确定调，
okay, so we're going to learn that skill to a couple of tricks for that.
所以我们将学习这项技能和一些技巧。
And that's basically all we're going to cover this time,
这就是我们这一次要讲的全部内容，
lots of exciting things to learn this week
这周有很多令人兴奋的东西要学习，
as you seek to become the musician, that you've always wanted to be.
当你想成为你一直想成为的音乐家。
So, I'll see you there.
所以，我们在那里见。
Okay, the first thing we need to do,
好的，我们需要做的第一件事，
as we as we need to cover these fifth string barre forms,
我们要介绍第五弦横按和弦，
that we're going to come up on,
我们将要出现的这些，
because we need to talk about hand position again,
因为我们需要再次讨论手的位置，
just review proper hand position is so vital to what we're doing,
回顾正确的手的位置对我们所做的非常重要，
what you need to remember keep that first finger straight,
你需要记住的是，保持食指伸直，
if you're angling back on you're a neck of your guitar like this,
如果你像这样倾斜在你的吉他琴颈上，
you're not going to get the power that you need,
你不会得到你需要的力量，
even though you think you're getting a whole lot of power,
即使你认为你得到了很大的力量，
but you're not getting the power where you need,
但你不会得到你需要的力量，
which is in that first finger,
在食指上（的力量），
make sure that first finger is nice and strong,
确保食指是好的和有力的，
okay, you need to take your finger to the gym
好的，你需要把你的手指带到健身房，
for these little muscles by doing those finger exercises,
通过做那些手指练习来锻炼这些小肌肉，
that's what toughens them up
这是让它们变得更强壮的地方，
and where it can do what it needs to do,
它可以做它需要做的事情，
you'll find that these fifth string barre forms
你会发现这些第五弦横按形式
are a little bit easier than the six string barre forms, that we've covered,
比我们已经介绍的第六弦横按形式更容易一些，
make sure that wrist is forward and low,
确保手腕是向前的而且低的，
the [] is to bring it back,
[]是把它带回来，
you want it down,
你希望它向下，
not completely whacked out, not uncomfortable,
不是完全被击倒，不是不舒服，
but it needs to, it needs to be good solid down, when you're playing,
但当你演奏时，它需要很好地稳固，
to have a good hand position,
有一个好的手的位置，
remember your hand position should still be balanced our fingers,
记住你的手的位置应该仍然平衡我们的手指，
even though we're playing barre chords,
即使我们在弹横按和弦，
they still should be coming at, not angled like this,
它们仍然不应该像这样倾斜，
but coming straight on, like that.
而是笔直地向前，像这样。
Okay.
好的。
Now, when you move between chords,
现在，当你在和弦之间移动时，
let's say I'm going from a G chord to an A chord,
假设我从 G 和弦变成 A 和弦，
I don't want to make the G chord
我不想做 G 和弦，
and then completely reset to make A chord,
然后完全重置来做 A 和弦，
I want to shift, not reset my fingers,
我想要移动而不是重置我的手指，
when I'm moving these chords in between positions,
当我在不同的位置之间移动这些和弦时，
if I go from a G to an A,
如果我从 G 变成 A ，
I just lift the pressure off
我只是把压力降下来，
and bring it up to an A,
把手放到 A ，
put the pressure back down again,
再把压力加上去，
you want to try and avoid,
你想要避免的，
as we're getting now, more and more chords
就像我们现在得到的，越来越多的和弦，
not to have to reset and take your hand off,
不必重置，把你的手拿开，
find the place, then reform the chord,
找到位置，然后重新形成和弦，
just move to where you need to go,
只是移动到你需要去的地方，
keep the hands basically your fingers basically in the same position
保持你的手指在相同的位置，
and then you're ready to hit.
然后你准备好了。
Okay, now let's talk about the notes on the fifth string,
好的，现在我们来谈谈第五弦上的音符，
that's where it all starts,
这就是所有的开始，
remember how we did the notes on the sixth string,
记得我们是如何做第六弦上的音符的，
now we're going to learn the notes on the fifth string.
现在我们要学习第五弦上的音符。
Okay, this is the A string,
好的，这是 A 弦，
same rules still apply,
同样的规则仍然适用，
half step between what two pairs of notes, E and F and B and C,
半音处于两对音符之间， E 和 F ， B 和 C ，
so let's count it up on the A string,
所以让我们在 A 弦上数一下，
you ready,
你准备好了吗，
A, B, C, you should already know those,
A B C ，你应该已经知道了，
now we need a whole step up to a D,
现在我们需要一个全音到 D ，
now we want to go to a E, that's a whole step,
现在我们到 E ，这是一个全音，
now we want to go to F, that's whatever half steps,
现在我们到 F ，这是一个半音，
need to go to G, that would be a whole step
到 G ，这是一个全音，
and A, up here at the twelfth fret, that would be a whole step,
A ，到第十二品，这是一个全音，
remember the magical twelve fret,
记得神奇的第十二品，
that's where everything starts repeating,
这就是一切开始重复的地方，
so that's where we would expect an A to be,
所以这就是我们期待 A 所在的地方，
okay, is right there at that twelve fret.
好的，就在那里，第十二品。
Let's do it one more time,
让我们再来一次，
A B C D E F G A.
A B C D E F G A 。
Let's go ahead and go back down
让我们继续，往下，
you try and say and play them as we're doing this,
当我们做的时候，你试着唱和弹奏它们，
A G F E D C B A.
A G F E D C B A 。
Now, just like we had five forms of the six string barre forms,
现在，就像我们有五种形式的第六弦形式，
we're going to have five forms of our other, of our fifth string barre forms,
我们将有五种形式在第五弦横按形式，
now lets review the six string first,
现在，首先让我们复习一下第六弦，
we have our F,
我们有 F ，
we learned Fm,
我们学到了 Fm ，
we learned F7,
我们学到了 F7 ，
we learned Fm7
我们学到了 Fm7 ，
and we learned Fsus.
我们学到了 Fsus 。
Okay, one more thing,
好的，还有一件事，
before we dive into these fifth string barre forms,
在我们深入到这些第五弦横按形式之前，
let's give you a little bit more practice at jumping around on that fifth string,
让我们给你更多的练习在第五弦上跳来跳去，
so I'm going to say note,
所以我来说音符，
you try and find it,
你试着找到它，
okay we're jumping around again.
好的，我们再次跳来跳去。
What if I said C, where's the C at on that fifth string,
如果我说 C ， C 在第五弦的哪里，
okay, right here at the third fret,
好的，就在第三品上，
let's jump around a little bit, what about an F,
让我们跳一下，那么 F 呢，
where would an F be, you find it,
F 在哪里，你找到它，
counted up, C D E F,
数一下， C D E F ，
what about a Bb,
Bb 怎么样，
well, that gets down to our first position,
这就是我们的第一个位置，
we should be pretty familiar with that, Bb,
我们应该很熟悉， Bb ，
what about Eb,
Eb 怎么样，
counted up, A B C D E,
数一下， A B C D E ，
flat, right there at the sixth fret,
降调，就在第六品上，
let's do a couple more,
我们再做几个，
Ab, where would Ab be,
Ab ， Ab 在哪里，
well, there's A,
好的，这里是 A ，
I can't, again I can't get any lower that way,
我不能顺着这个方向再低了，
so the answer is not that way,
所以答案不是这个方向，
the answer is up high,
答案在高的方向，
twelve fret, there's A, Ab, is there.
第十二品是 A ， Ab 在这里。
Okay, couple more,
好的，再来几个，
D#,
D# ，
D#, A B C D,
D# ， A B C D ，
D# would be there.
D# 在这里。
Now, let's jump around on both strings for a second,
现在，让我们在两根弦上跳跃，
okay, if I want you to find a G on both strings,
好的，如果我想让你在两根弦上都找到 G ，
where would it be,
它会在哪里，
well, here's a G here on the sixth string
好的，这里有一个 G 在第六弦上，
and the G on the fifth string would be way up here,
第五弦上的 G 应该在这里，
if I wanted to C on both of those strings,
如果我想要这两根弦上的 C ，
well, C on the sixth string is here,
第六弦上的 C 在这里，
C on the fifth string is there.
第五弦上的 C 在这里。
Let's do two more,
让我们再做两个，
Eb,
Eb ，
well, Eb on the sixth string,
好的，第六弦上的 Eb ，
not the twelve frets, at the eleventh fret, one fret down,
不是第十二品，在第十一品，下来一品，
and on the fifth string, would be at the sixth fret.
在第五根弦上，在第六品。
One more, what do you say about an F#,
再来一个， F# 怎么样，
second fret on the sixth string,
第六弦的第二品，
that what is that ninth fret on the fifth string.
第五弦上的第九品。
Jumping from string to string is going to be an important concept,
从一个弦跳到另一个弦将是一个重要的概念，
when we start putting these forms together.
当我们开始把这些形式组合在一起时。
Now, let's talk about the five forms that are based off the fifth string,
现在让我们来谈谈基于第五弦的五个形式，
okay, on the fifth string barre chords,
好的，第五弦上的横按和弦，
the first one I want to take a look at is Bm,
我想看的第一个是 Bm ，
okay, Bm, okay,
好的， Bm ，好的，
that we barre,
我们横按，
again, we barre five strings with our first finger,
再次，我们用食指横按五根弦，
if you want to overshoot a little bit, that's fine,
如果你想超过一点，没关系，
you can bump into that six string as long as,
你可以碰上第六弦，
you don't play it,
你不弹奏它，
when you're playing down here, we just get five strings.
当你演奏的时候，我们只弹五根弦。
Okay, so you barre all of those,
好的，所以你横按这些，
now I need my third finger on that fourth fret,
现在我需要我的无名指在第四品，
pinky underneath him
小拇指在它下面，
and that second finger on that,
中指在那里，
now just just make sure that you're basing these off of the second fret,
只需确保这些是基于第二品的，
because remember B is on that second fret,
因为记住， B 在第二品，
so where F we were down here at this first fret,
所以， F 在第一品，
we've pretty much done everything down to the first fret,
我们几乎做所有的事情在第一品，
for these we shift up a little bit,
我们向下到移动一点，
and the B, we're pivoting off of this B,
B ，我们向上移动一点，
so our first finger is actually on that second fret position.
所以我们的食指在第二品位置。
Okay, so there's Bm,
好的，这是 Bm ，
what about B7,
那么 B7 呢，
well, take my second finger off
把我的食指拿开，
and I put my pinky down on that second string,
把我的小拇指放在第二弦上，
okay, maybe do one more time,
好的，也许再来一次，
make sure all these notes are sounding out nice and clear,
确保所有这些音符听起来都很清晰，
what about Bm7,
那么 Bm7 呢，
well, I put my second finger down and take my pinky off again,
好的，我把食指放下来，然后再次拿开小拇指，
got my barre down nice and strong,
横按要又好又有力，
if it sounds little buzzy on a couple of notes,
如果在几个音符上听起来有点嗡嗡作响，
try and get good position on it,
试着在它上面找到合适的位置，
strengthen up that first finger a little bit,
加强一下食指，
got Bm7.
得到 Bm7 。
Now, Bsus is the next one I want to cover,
现在 Bsus 是接下来我要讲的，
that has my pinky down, like on the B7,
使我的小拇指向下，就像 B7 ，
but I shift my pinky out a half step,
但把我的小拇指向外移了半音，
wow, so I got a pretty good stretch on that one,
哇，我得到了一个相当好的伸展，
that's a Bsus.
这是 Bsus 。
Okay, and I'm just hitting the five strings,
好的，我只是拨动五根弦，
don't accidentally hit that six string,
不要不小心碰到第六弦，
accuracy counts and guitar playing,
精确的计数，吉他演奏，
you're just going for five strings,
你只需要五根弦，
make sure you get all five,
确保你得到了全部五根弦，
you gotta stretch that pinky out a little bit, get him loosened up,
你必须稍微伸展一下小拇指，让它放松，
remember we always do our finger exercise strengthen,
记住，我们总是做手指练习，
that limber up that hand a little bit,
活动你的手，
if your pinky doesn't want to do that initially,
如果你的小拇指一开始不想这样做，
remember limber up in your hand takes time, just like stretching takes time,
记住，伸展你的手需要时间，就像伸展需要时间，
if you want to start stretching with big muscles,
如果你想开始伸展大肌肉，
same way with little muscles,
同样的方法对于小肌肉，
even though you may not be able to get that right now,
即使你现在可能不能做到，
that doesn't mean you're ever going to get it,
这并不意味着你永远都得不到它，
just means you need to limber up that hand a little bit.
只意味着你需要伸展那个手。
Bsus.
Bsus 。
Now the last one I want to cover is B,
现在最后一个我想介绍的是 B ，
now you may think that should have been the first,
你可能认为这应该是第一个，
well, there's a couple of problems with B,
好的， B 有几个问题，
there's two different ways you can finger it,
有两种不同的手指方法，
you'll notice the first finger down there,
你注意到食指在这里，
I've got a barre all the way here
我在这里有一个横按，
and then I've got second third and fourth all squished in here,
然后我把中指、无名指、小拇指都挤在这里，
on that fourth fret
在第四品上，
and they're all squished right underneath each other,
它们都压在彼此下面，
which is pretty tricky to get,
这是相当难的，
when you're just starting out,
当你刚开始的时候，
so that's, that's the accurate way to play that,
所以这是正确的弹法，
that may be a little tricky for you,
这对你来说可能有点棘手，
an easier way, not quite as, as accurate way to play it,
一种更容易的方式，不是那么准确的弹法，
but an easier way
但这是一种更简单的方式，
and a lot of guys use it,
很多人都用它，
so it's nothing wrong with it,
所以这没什么错，
is they take this B
他们按住这个 B ，
and then they just barre all three of these with your third finger,
然后他们用无名指横按这三个，
see that,
看到了吗，
so instead of doing this,
所以，不是这样做，
they just barre that,
他们只是横按，
now the problem is,
现在的问题是，
is that you can't play that last string,
你不能弹奏最后一根弦，
you end up with a dead string there,
你会在那里有一根死弦，
so, or if you're sloppy you barre the whole thing
或者，如果你很草率，你横按所有的弦，
and you end up with the wrong chord,
你最终得到错误的和弦，
so either gotta get off that string or don't play that last string.
所以要么离开那根弦，要么不弹奏最后一根弦。
Okay, so this way you can play all five of them,
好的，这种方式，你弹奏所有五根弦，
with this form, you just do the inside four.
这种形式，你只需要弹奏里面的四根。
See how that works,
看到它是如何工作的，
okay, those are basically the five forms,
好的，这些基本上是五种形式，
let's go through a couple of the exercises that you have in your book.
让我们来看看你书中的几个练习。
Okay, let's look at some of those barre chord exercises on the fifth string,
好的，让我们看一下第五弦上的横按和弦练习，
using our fifth string barre forms.
用我们的第五弦横按形式。
Okay, number one, starts out with that b minor,
好的，第一个从 Bm 开始，
okay, here we go,
好的，我们开始，
form it, finger nice and straight, wrist low and forward,
形式，手指笔直，手腕低而且向前，
here we go, Bm,
我们开始， Bm ，
ready go, two three four,
准备，开始， 2 3 4 ，
now you need to slide up just one half step up to Cm,
现在你只需要往上滑半音就到 Cm ，
remember we talked about sliding,
记得我们说过滑动，
don't reposition every note,
不是每个音符都重新定位，
just let up the pressure,
只是放松压力，
scoot up your hand a half step,
把你的手向上半音，
now, you're a Cm,
现在，你是 Cm ，
now, we're gonna scoot up to Dm, two three,
现在，我们要上升到 Dm ， 2 3 ，
one more scoop up to Em,
再次上升到 Em ，
let's jump back down to Bm.
让我们跳回到 Bm 。
Good, see how that works,
好的，看到这是怎么回事，
if you try to reset your chord every time,
如果你每次都试着重置你的和弦，
you'll find that that slows you way down,
你会发现这会减慢你的速度，
just get practice that a little bit,
只要练习一下，
playing a chord, releasing it,
弹奏和弦，释放它，
you don't need to bring your fingers off the strings,
你不需要把手指从琴弦上拿开，
just release the pressure,
只需要释放压力，
shift your hand up to where it needs to be,
把你的手向上移到需要的地方，
put the pressure back down,
把压力放回去，
it's a lot more efficient in your chord with that.
这会让你更有效率，在弹和弦的时候。
Let's look at number two,
让我们看看第二个，
starts on that Bm again,
再次从 Bm 开始，
ready, play,
准备，弹奏，
now, C major, so I shift up to C,
现在， C 大调，所以我移动到 C ，
and if I can squeeze all my fingers in there,
如果我能把所有的手指都挤进去，
I get C major,
我就能得到 C 大调，
then I go back down to Bm,
然后我回到 Bm ，
now shift up to D,
现在移动到 D ，
I'm gonna use that other form,
我要用另一种形式，
but have to remember, don't hit that last string.
但必须记住，不要碰到最后一根弦。
Okay, let's do that one again,
好的，让我们再来一次，
Bm, C, Bm, D.
Bm C Bm D 。
Good, now let's shift it up a little bit,
好的，现在我们把它调高一点，
let's skip over to number five,
让我们跳到第五个，
okay, let's see, number five starts on that Eb,
好的，让我们看看，第五个从 Eb 开始，
right here,
就在这里，
ready go, two three,
准备，开始， 2 3 ，
Cm7, jump down to C,
Cm7 ，调到 C ，
just continue that same rhythm
继续相同的节奏，
and Fm7, big jump up to the what is that fifth six seventh fret, eighth fret,
Fm7 ，跳到 5 6 7 品，第八品，
jump big, jump down to Bbsus, all the way at the end,
跳到 Bbsus ，一直到最后面，
bring that pinky up, Bb7,
把小拇指拿上来， Bb7 ，
Eb.
Eb 。
Alright, now this time in our how music works section,
好的，这次在我们的音乐原理部分，
we're going to talk about major scales.
我们将讨论大调音阶。
Okay, remember the major scale pattern that we talked about,
好的，记得我们所说的大调音阶模式，
whole whole half, whole whole whole half,
全音，全音，半音，全音，全音，全音，半音，
two wholes and a half, three wholes and a half,
两个全音，一个半音，三个全音，一个半音，
now you'll notice, as you did all of those
你注意到，你已经做过它们，
and hopefully you did them and did them and did them,
希望你做过很多次，
as you did,
正如你所做的，
all you came up with a certain combination of sharps and flats for each particular key,
你为每个特定的调设计特定的升调和降调的组合，
that's what we're going to talk about now,
这就是我们现在要讨论的，
that's key signatures.
那就是调号。
Now, when we talked earlier,
当我们在之前讨论的，
in some of the earlier sessions,
在之前的一些课程中，
I just mentioned that at the beginning of a piece of music,
我提到在一首音乐的开头，
sometimes you'll see a sharp, just right after the clef sign,
有时你会看到一个升调符号，就在谱号后面，
something like that,
就像这样，
that's what that is,
就是这样，
that's a key signature,
这是一个调号，
now we're going to tell you why that key signature is there,
现在我要告诉你为什么那个调号在那里，
how that key signature is developed,
这个调号是如何产生的，
it's not just random,
它不仅仅是随机的，
that in a particular song,
在一首特定的歌曲中，
let's say there's an F sharp in the key signature,
假设在调号中有一个 F 升调，
that all Fs are sharp,
所有的 F 都是升调的，
we're going to determine that that is actually in the key of G,
我们将确定这实际上是 G 调，
and the key of G has one sharp in it
G 调有一个升调，
from our scales that we learned last time,
从我们上一次学到的音阶，
and that sharp is always f sharp,
而那个升调总是 F 升调，
sharps and flats come in a specific order,
升调和降调会有一个特定的顺序，
as you're writing them in key signatures,
当你在调号中写下它们时，
the first sharp,
第一个升调，
no matter whether I have one or seven is always going to be F sharp,
不管我有[一个]或七个，总是 F# ，
it could think of it like a pyramid,
可以把它想象成一座金字塔，
the key with one #, it would be F#,
调有一个 # ，它就是 F# ，
then if you had two #s, it would be F# and C#,
如果你有两个 # ，它将是 F# C# ，
and if you have three #s, it would be F#, C# and G#,
如果你有三个 # ，它们是 F# C# 和 G# ，
they build on each other like that,
它们是这样建立起来的，
so I wouldn't put them out of order,
所以我不会把它们放在一起，
if we start thinking of them out of order,
如果我们开始把它们想得乱七八糟，
it won't make sense, when you're looking at key signatures,
当你看调号的时候，就没有意义了，
they come in a very specific order,
它们以非常具体的顺序出现，
F# first, F# C#, F# C# G# and so on, from there,
第一个是 F# ， F# C# ， F# C# G# 等等，
okay, so order is very important.
好的，所以顺序是非常重要的。
Now, we talked about major scales,
现在，我们已经讨论了大调音阶，
now I'm going to adjust it a little bit
现在我要稍微调整一下，
and we're going to talk about minor scales,
我们要谈到小调音阶，
now there's all kinds of different minor scales,
现在有各种不同的小调音阶，
I play guitar for living,
我以弹吉他为生，
I don't use all of those scales,
我没有使用所有这些小调，
the only other minor scale other than a natural minor,
除了自然小调，
I have ever used is a harmonic minor,
我唯一使用过的其他小调是和声小调，
some guys get all busy and bent out of shape
有些人忙于
learning all these different minor forms,
学习所有这些不同的小调形式，
you don't need to know that.
你不需要知道这些。
How I think of minor scales,
我对小调音阶的看法，
it's not a whole new world,
这并不是一个全新的世界，
you relate everything back to a major scale,
你把一切都与大调音阶联系起来，
a major scale, let's take a C major scale,
大调音阶，让我们以 C 大调音阶为例，
it goes from C, D E F G A B C, C to C,
它从 C 开始， D E F G A B C ， C 到 C ，
to get a minor scale from that,
为了得到一个小调音阶，
I go down, actually think of it like a number line,
我往下，把它想象成一条数字线，
you know it starts at C and then it just goes to C and it keeps going,
它从 C 开始，到 C ，然后一直往下走，
if I want to get a minor scale,
如果我想要一个小调音阶，
I just take that major scale
我只需要用那个大调音阶，
and I shifted down a couple of steps, two steps.
然后我调低几个音，两个音。
So, now I'm doing,
所以，现在我要做的，
I'm still in the key of C,
我现在仍然是在 C 调，
no sharps or no flats,
没有升调，也没有降调，
but I'm starting on an A,
但我从 A 开始，
so I'm going now from A to A, not from C to C,
所以我现在从 A 到 A ，而不是从 C 到 C ，
but I'm still in the key of C, no sharps or flats,
但我仍然是在 C 调上，没有升调，也没有降调，
so I end up with A B C D E F G A,
所以我最终得到了 A B C D E F G A ，
that is a minor scale,
这是一个小调音阶，
what we call in the business a natural minor scale,
我们在商业中称之为自然小调音阶，
okay, those are built off of the major scales,
好的，这些是建立在大调音阶之上的，
there's a special relationship between that minor and the major scale,
在小调音阶和大调音阶之间有一种特殊的关系，
it's called parallel, we hear that term floated around a lot,
这被称为平行，我们听到了这个术语。
we'll talk a lot about that,
我们会讲很多东西，
things something is a parallel major or a parallel minor,
比如平行大调，或者平行小调，
what that means is, if I'm in the key of C,
这意味着，如果我是 C 调的话，
and I want to get to the minor key,
我想要拿到小调，
I can either go down too,
我要么向下去，
or it's probably easier for you to think of it,
要么你们更容易想到，
if I go to the sixth step of a C major scale,
如果我从 C 大调走六步，
that would be A, right, C D E F G A,
这将是 A ，是吧， C D E F G A ，
now I'm a A,
现在我是一个 A ,
A minor is the parallel major of C major,
A 小调是 C 大调的平行大调，
and vice versa,
反之亦然，
if, if I'm in C major, I want the parallel minor, it's A minor,
如果我在 C 大调，我想要平行小调，它是 A 小调，
if I'm an A minor and I want the parallel major, it's C major.
如果我是 A 小调，我想要平行大调，它要 C 大调。
Okay, let's do it, let's figure out another one,
好的，让我们想出另一个，
what if I'm an F major,
如果我是 F 大调怎么办，
what would be the parallel minor of F major,
F 大调的平行小调是什么，
well, I just go up to the sixth step,
好的，我向上六步，
F G A Bb C D,
F G A Bb C D ，
and that would be by parallel minor,
那就是平行小调，
see how that works,
看到它是如何工作的，
now let's talk about keys a little bit.
现在让我们来讨论一下调。
Okay, we touched on keys and key signatures a little bit earlier,
好的，我们之前讨论了调和调号，
so now let's put into work,
现在让我们开始工作，
for example in the key of F,
例如在 F 调中，
when you were doing your scale,
当你在做音阶时，
you had, what was different,
有什么不同，
what had a sharp or flat by,
什么有一个升调或降调，
you'll notice the fourth step, Bb,
你会注意到第四步， Bb ，
is the only thing that had a flat or sharp in it,
是唯一有升调或降调的东西，
so we would say that the key signature for the key of F has one flat, Bb.
所以我们可以说 F 的调号有一个降调， Bb 。
Let's do another one,
让我们再做一个，
so if the key signature has two sharps in it,
所以如果调号中有两个升调符号，
an F# and C#,
一个是 F# ，一个是 C# ，
then we are in the key of D.
那么我们在 D 调中。
Now, let me tell you a very important trick that you can learn,
现在让我告诉你一个可以学到的非常重要的诀窍，
how to tell what key a piece of music is in,
如何辨别一首音乐的调是什么，
there's two different ways we're going to talk about it,
我们有两种不同的方式来谈论它，
in your first example there,
在你的第一个示例中，
you'll see that the key signature has an F# in it,
你看到调号中有一个 F# ，
therefore, if you go back to the scales,
因此，如果你回到音阶，
you'll know that the only key that has one sharp in it is the key of G,
你知道唯一有一个升调的是 G 调，
so you can solve it that way by by knowing your scales.
所以你可以通过知道你的音阶来解决它。
The second example, let's do that,
第二个例子，让我们这样做，
it has a Bb Eb and Ab,
它有 Bb Eb Ab ，
well, what's scale uses a Bb Eb and Ab,
哪个音阶使用 Bb Eb Ab ，
well, that would be the key of Eb.
那就是 Eb 调。
Okay, here's another trick,
好的，这是另一个诀窍，
that's a little bit easier to learn,
学习要容易一些，
how to tell what keys a piece of music in,
如何辨别一段音乐的调，
it has two different parts,
它有两个不同的部分，
of the first part of it in sharp keys,
第一部分在升调，
for sharp keys, the rule is,
对于升调，规则是，
how to tell a key,
如何辨别调，
the key is one half step up from the last sharp in the key signature,
调比调号中最后一个升调高半音，
I'll say that again,
我要再说一次，
the rule is for sharp keys,
规则是针对升调的，
the key is one half step up from the last sharp in the key signature,
调比调号中最后一个升调高半音，
for example, if the key signature has an F#, a C# and G#,
例如，调号中有 F# C# G# ，
then the last sharp is a G#,
最后一个升调是 G# ，
that's the one you're looking at,
这就是你要找的，
one half step up from a G# is A,
比 G# 高半音的是 A ，
so the key is A.
所以调是 A 。
Okay, what about for flat keys,
好的，那么降调呢，
well, here's the rule for flat keys,
好的，这是针对降调的规则，
the rule says the key is the next to last flat in the key signature,
规则规定，调是调号中倒数第二个降调，
so you take the key signature and derive it from there,
所以你拿到调号，从那里派生出来，
so, for example, if the key signature has a Bb Eb and an Ab in it,
例如，如果调号有 Bb Eb Ab ，
the next to last flat is Eb,
倒数第二个降调是 Eb ，
that's the one you're looking at,
这就是你要找的那个，
so the key is Eb.
所以调是 Eb 。
Learning your major scales and the keys that come from them takes time,
学习大调音阶和来自它们的音调需要时间，
like learning your multiplication tables,
就像学习乘法表一样，
we talked about that,
我们已经讨论过了，
you just can't solve them one time and expect to know
你不能只解一次就期望知道答案，
and you've got to do them over and over and over again
你必须一遍又一遍地做，
until they get to be memorized,
直到它们被记住，
build these scales,
构建这些音阶，
look at the flats and sharps use,
看看使用的降调和升调，
look at the key signatures and take some time to memorize them.
看看调号，花点时间记住它们。
Here's our assignment for this week,
这是我们这周的作业，
your assignment is,
你的作业是，
learn the five forms that we did on the fifth string,
学习我们在第五弦上做的五种形式，
those fifth string basic barre forms,
这些第五弦的基本横按形式，
okay, we're going to learn a new song Jamaica Farewell,
我们要学习一首新歌 Jamaica Farewell ，
the main name might not be familiar,
主要名字可能不熟悉，
but I'm pretty sure that the melody will be familiar to you
但我非常确定你会熟悉旋律，
in two different keys F and G,
两个不同的调 F 和 G ，
okay, complete those key signature worksheets that we have in your book
好的，完成你书中的调号工作表，
and I'll see you at the workshop.
我们在 workshop 上见。
Okay, welcome to the workshop time,
好的，欢迎来到 workshop 时间，
let's get some working knowledge of all these concepts, that we talked about.
让我们了解一下我们所说的这些概念的实用知识。
Okay, first thing we do review all of your basic barre chord forms,
好的，首先我们要复习一下你们所有的基本横按和弦形式，
our six string forms,
我们的第六弦形式，
let's go through those, let's go through them,
让我们弹奏它们，
like like we're in the key of A,
比如我们在 A 调，
so, play an A, Am, A7, Am7, Asus,
所以，弹奏 A Am A7 Am7 Asus ，
okay, got those five forms.
好的，得到这五种形式。
Now, we're going to do the ones in on the fifth string forms, that we learned,
现在我们要做我们学到的第五弦上的形式，
let's do those in B,
让我们在 B 中做这些，
so we've got a B,
所以我们得到 B ，
either way that you want to finger that,
无论哪种按法，
we've got Bm, B7, Bm7, and Bsus.
我们得到 Bm B7 Bm7 Bsus 。
We'll go through those one more time,
我们再来一遍，
B, Bm, B7, Bm7 and Bsus.
B Bm B7 Bm7 Bsus 。
Okay, now take a look at some of the basic barre chord exercises for the fifth string,
好的，现在看一下第五弦的一些基本的横按和弦练习，
let's go through a couple of those,
让我们做一些练习，
let's start with number one,
让我们从第一个开始，
Bm, starts it, ready go, two three four,
Bm ，开始，准备，开始， 2 3 4 ，
Cm, remember just slide up,
Cm ，记得往上滑就行了，
Dm, two three,
Dm ， 2 3 ，
Em, two three.
Em ， 2 3 。
Let's do it again,
让我们再来一次，
Bm, jump down, two three four,
Bm ，跳下来， 2 3 4 ，
Cm,
Cm ，
Dm,
Dm ，
Em.
Em 。
Number two, let's go,
第二个，让我们开始，
Bm, ready, play,
Bm ，准备，弹奏，
C,
C ，
back to Bm,
回到 Bm ，
repeat it.
重复一遍。
Number three, ready, go,
第三个，准备，开始，
try and move as fast as you can between those chords,
试着在这些和弦中以最快的速度移动，
Em7,
Em7 ，
C, another one,
C ，再来一次，
two three four.
2 3 4 。
Take a look at number four too,
再看一下第四个，
ready go,
准备，开始，
let me stop you,
让我停止一下，
when you're strumming,
当你扫弦时，
you're accurate going down remember five strings,
你准确地向下弹奏五根弦，
but when you come up, you just hit a couple of them,
但当你向上的时候，你只碰到几根，
okay, so you're still doing down and up,
好的，你仍然在做向下和向上，
but you're accurate going down,
但是你准确地向下，
[] just had a couple of them, coming up,
向上时，只有其中几个，
okay, armed with that information,
好了，有了这些信息，
let's try number four,
让我们试试第四个，
ready, go,
准备，开始，
two three four.
2 3 4 。
Okay, let's get down to number six,
好的，让我们到第六个，
okay, number six starts at a G,
好的，第六个从 G 开始，
way up at the top of your neck,
在你的琴颈上方，
okay, I'm going to use the alternate forms,
好的，我将使用替代形式，
it's probably little bit easier for me to do it
这对我来说可能更容易一些，
rather than squeezing all your fingers in like that,
而不是像这样把所有的手指都挤进去，
the higher you get up the neck,
你在琴颈上越高，
of course the less space you have,
当然你的空间就越小，
you may need to do some of that.
你可能需要做一些这样的事情。
Okay, number six, ready go,
好的，第六个，准备，开始，
down up, up,
下上，上，
Eb, D, Dsus,
Eb D Dsus ，
back to D
回到 D ，
and a G, two three.
G ， 2 3 。
Let's do that again, G,
我们再来一次， G ，
Dsus, D, G, two three four.
Dsus D G ， 2 3 4 。
Okay, to seven, our last one here,
好的，第七个，我们这里的最后一个，
we'll pick it up a little bit,
我们会稍微快一点，
starts on that Bb,
从那个 Bb 开始，
ready, go.
准备，开始。
One more time, seven and go.
再来一次，第七个，开始。
Now just a final, take it up a little bit faster,
现在最后一次，再快一点，
ready, go.
准备，开始。
Very good,
很好，
okay, now let's take a look at our song Jamaica Farewell,
好的，现在让我们来看看歌曲 Jamaica Farewell ，
okay, we're going to first do it in the key of F,
我们将首先用 F 调来弹，
what is the key of F have in it, one flat,
什么在 F 调中，一个降调，
okay, let's take a look at the melody first,
好的，让我们先看一下旋律，
I'll play it one time through slowly
我会慢慢地弹一遍，
and then we'll do one time through fast,
然后我们快弹一遍，
starting it slowly, in F,
先从 F 慢慢开始，
ready, go,
准备，开始，
rest, rest,
休息，休息，
very good, that's you do.
非常好。
Alright, now let's play through one time fast,
好的，现在我们弹一遍快的，
ready, go,
准备，开始，
rest, rest.
休息，休息。
Okay, now I'm going to play it through one time in G
好的，现在我要使用 G 弹一遍，
and we'll play it at the faster tempo now,
我们用更快的节奏演奏它，
that you've got a handle on it, okay,
既然你已经掌握了，
ready go,
准备，开始，
rest, rest.
休息，休息。
Great, okay, now let's do the chords,
很好，好的，现在让我们做和弦，
[] should try and use barre chords on this
应该试着在这里使用横按和弦，
rather than doing the open chords,
而不是做开放和弦，
I know you can do the open chords,
我知道你可以做开放和弦，
let's get some barre practice on all this stuff,
让我们在所有这些东西上进行一些横按练习，
okay, just do one chord for each barre measure at this point,
好的，在这一点上，每个小节只做一个和弦，
okay, starts on a G,
好的，从 G 开始，
ready, go, two three,
准备，开始， 2 3 ，
C, now I would jump down to the fifth string and do the C there,
C ，现在我要跳到第五弦上，在那里做 C ，
D7,
D7 ，
then back to G, down low,
然后回到 G ，低音，
generally I want to try to keep things low,
一般来说，我想保持低音，
I don't want to jump to that eight fret,
我不想跳到第八品上，
I want to stay right that third fret,
我想保持在第三品，
because things are more comfortable down there,
因为事情在这里更舒服，
one more G here, two three four,
再一个 G ， 2 3 4 ，
C, two three four,
C ， 2 3 4 ，
two three four,
2 3 4 ，
last line,
最后一行，
C, two three,
C ， 2 3 ，
here we get G for two beats, D for two beats,
这里我们 G 两个节拍， D 两个节拍，
back to G.
回到 G 。
Very good,
非常好，
just for a second, let's talk about key signatures and keys,
稍微花点时间，让我们讨论一下调和调号，
okay, remember how parallel major and minor work,
好的，记得平行大调和小调是如何工作的，
in order to find a parallel minor,
为了找到平行的小调，
you go down two steps from a major scale,
你从一个大调音阶下降两级，
or you can go up six steps,
或者你可以上升六级，
either way gets you to the same note.
无论哪种方式，你都会得到相同的音符。
So a C major, remember what equal an A minor,
所以 C 大调等于 A 小调，
F major equals D minor,
F 大调等于 D 小调，
okay, let's practice,
好的，让我们练习一下，
a G major what would that be the parallel minor,
G 大调的平行小调是什么，
E minor,
E 小调，
what about G minor, what would be the parallel major there,
那 G 小调呢，它的平行大调是什么，
Bb major,
Bb 大调，
what about Eb major, what would the parallel minor be,
Eb 大调呢，它的平行小调是什么，
C minor,
C 小调，
what about if a key has four sharps in it,
如果一个调有四个升调，
they're an F# C# G# and D#,
它们是 F# C# G# D# ，
what key are we in there,
我们在那里是什么调，
E,
是 E ，
remember the rule, you go a half step up from the last sharp,
记住规则，你从最后一个升调上升半音，
the last sharp is D#,
最后一个升调是 D# ，
half step up from that would be an E.
从那里上升半音就是 E 。
Great, so my encouragement to you would be memorize those keys,
很好，所以我鼓励你们记住那些调，
memorize those scales,
记住那些音阶，
learn the fifth and sixth string barre forms,
学习第五弦和第六弦横按形式，
be able to play them without buzzing,
能够在没有嗡嗡声的情况下演奏它们，
remember it takes time to get a good sound on barre chords,
记住，在横按和弦上获得好的声音是需要时间的，
do all the exercises that we given to you,
做我们给你的所有练习，
don't just conquer them one time,
不只是征服它们一次，
go back through them again,
再试一次，
strengthen those fingers up, to do what they need to do,
加强你的手指做他们需要做的事情，
more songs are available in your book
你的书里有更多的歌曲，
and for more practice, check out the Jam Along CDs as well,
如果需要更多的练习，也可以看看 Jam Along CD ，
we'll see you next time.
我们下次再见。